ALEXANDER GRABOWSKI

CONTACT

https://xangrab.com/

https://github.com/XanGrab/

nttps://xangrab.itch.io/

in /alexander-xander-grabowski-8164481a1/

PROFILE

I have been professionally developing games for the last two years, and recreationally my entire life. I am proficient in a diverse range of full-stack toolchains targeting game and web development. I can frequently be found in international fan games, hackathons, and game jams, expressing my passion for applied learning games and FOSS. I developed a sense of leadership early, achieving the rank of Eagle Scout, and continued developing my leadership skills guiding competitive e-sports teams to compete at the national level. I am a lifelong, self-driven learner and problem solver.

SKILLS

- Game Engines
 - Unity
 - Godot
 - Phaser
- Graphics Libraries
 - Pixi.js
 - HLSL (Unity)
 - GLSL (Three.js)
- · Programming Languages
 - o C++
 - o C#
 - TypeScript
- Web Development Tools
 - Node.js
 - Vite
 - Webpack
- DevOps & Services
 - Github Actions
 - o Docker
 - Firebase BaaS
- · Digital Illustration & Wireframing
 - o Figma
 - Illustator
 - Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

Gameplay Programmer at *Field Day Learning Games* **2022.01–2023.05** https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/

Developer and junior designer on multiple projects including *Wake: Tales* from the Aqualab, client-side API for *Open Game Data*, and smaller browser-based HTML5 games.

Head Programming Instructor at Code Ninjas

2020.10-2022.12

https://codeninjas.com/

Developed programming curriculum for kids of various backgrounds in the K-12 age range spanning JavaScript, MakeCode Arcade, Roblox Studio, and the Unity game engine.

Youth Esports Coach at XP League

2020.10-2022.12

https://www.xpleague.com/

Certified youth eSports coach through the Positive Coaching Alliance. Led the Sun Prairie league's Fortnite team to compete at the North American Finals in 2022.

PROJECTS

MOTHER².

Unattached

2021-pres.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWeF1jRstLk

Released in 1994 as MOTHER 2 in Japan and as EarthBound in the West, MOTHER² is a full-length ground-up reimagining of the game by fans for fans.

- ♦ Designed and developed a multitude of features for the project contributing to over 35% of the entire codebase
- Conducted playtester surveys and interviews to inform the design of new features

WAKE: TALES FROM THE AQUALAB.

Field Day Learning Games

2022-2023

https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/play/wake/

An oceanography game targeting Chromebooks in middle school classrooms helping students learn scientific experimentation, modeling, and argumentation.

- \diamond Designed pivotal story and level layout elements of the introductory sequence for the game
- \diamond Brought gameplay systems to life in Unity, implementing user interfaces for the game's Shop, Observation Tanks, and Modeling
- \diamond Used in-house scripting tools to implement over 75% of the quests in the game

UNANNOUNCED HTML5 BROWSER GAMES.

Field Day Learning Games

2023

https://github.com/opengamedata/opengamedata-js-log/

Point-and-click, browser-based games targeting mobile tablets and other handheld devices.

- \diamond Built data analytics and logging tools for real-time data collection with Firebase in collaboration with the Open Game Data project
- ♦ Developed the game's dialogue system building text-parsing tooling which extended scripts written in YarnSpinner
- Adapted the game's graphics to make use of both WebGL and Canvas rendering styles to meet different tablet and mobile limitations

EDUCATION

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN CAPSTONE CERTIFICATE

University of Wisconsin-Madison

2023-pres.

2019-2023

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Wisconsin—Madison

• Certification (Minor) in Game Design

- Certification in Digital Art
- Certification in Professional Japanese Communication